We've just trained the PCA model and now we can access the underlying model parameters.
我们刚刚训练了 PCA 模型 现在我们可以访问底层模型参数
One thing that we'll need is the name of the training job.
我们需要训练作业的名称
I'm going to copy it from here,
我将从这里复制该名称
we could also get it from the AWS console.
还可以从 AWS 控制台中查看名称
Saved model artifacts are stored in S3 as a TAR file.
保存的模型工具以 TAR 文件形式存储在 S3 中
This is a compressed file in the output path that we
这是一个压缩文件
specified in the location output path,
位于我们指定的输出路径中
and it will also be saved in this output/model.tar.gz extension.
并且将保存在 output/model.tar.gz 中
We can explore the artifacts that are stored here and use them to deploy a trained model.
我们可以查看存储在这里的工件并使用它们部署训练过的模型
So in here, I'm going to copy and paste my training job name,
在这里复制粘贴训练作业的名称
and then the model key is going to be the prefix counties that we specified earlier,
model_key 将为之前指定的 prefix
this job name, and the output extension.
作业名称和输出扩展路径的组合
Then similar to how we downloaded the CSV file before,
与之前下载 csv 文件相似
we're going to pass in that model key, the bucket name,
我们将传入 model_key、bucket_name
and call download file on our boto3 resource.
并对 boto3.resource 调用 download_file
Then I actually have a couple more lines of code that will
还有几行代码
unzip this compressed file and store it as model_algo-1,
目的是解压缩这个文件并存储为 model_algo-1
this name is consistent across models.
这个名称在模型之间是一致的
So if this so executed,
如果执行此单元格
this should print out the model key and some confirmation code.
将输出 model_key 它是一个确认码
Now built-in SageMaker models are built on something called MXNet.
内置 SageMaker 模型是用 MXNet 构建的
So I'm importing this as a library mx,
所以导入 mx 库
and this gives us certain tools to use.
这样就可以获得一些能使用的工具
I'm going to load in the parameters of our model by name, which is model_algo-1.
通过传入模型名称 (model_algo-1) 加载模型的参数
The mx library allows me to load this in as an ndarray.
mx 库可以将这个加载为 ndarray
I'm saving all of these as the PCA model parameters and printing them out here.
将所有这些保存到 pca_model_params 中 并输出这些参数
I can see that this array holds three main values, s,
可以看到这个数组主要包含三个值
v, and down here a mean value,
分别是 s v 下面是 mean
and I'll be able to access these arrays by name.
我可以通过名称访问这些数组
I have some explanations of what each of these is here.
我在这里解释了每个值的含义
The mean is the mean that's subtracted from a component in order to center it,
mean 表示为了居中成分而减去的均值
this is part of the PCA calculation.
这属于 PCA 计算的一个步骤
v is the makeup of the principal components,
v 表示主成分的组成
so which linear combinations of original features make up each principal component?
即哪些原始特征线性组合组成了每个主成分
s are the singular values of the components.
s 表示成分的奇异值
Now, we talked about getting components that will cause the most variance in our dataset.
我们讨论了如何获得可以解释最大数据集方差的成分
s will not give us the exact percentage data variants,
s 并不能告诉我们精确的百分比数据方差
but it can help us calculate a good approximation,
但是可以根据这个近似解释方差公式
according to this approximate explained variance formula,
帮助我们计算出很逼近的方差百分比
which I'll go over in a bit.
稍后我会讲解这个公式的
The important thing to note is that,
需要注意的一点是
for looking at the principal components and the data variance,
在研究主成分和数据方差时
we'll be interested in v and s only.
我们只对 v 和 s 感兴趣
I'm actually going to load the specific parameters calling them by name,
我将通过名称加载这些参数
and loading them in as DataFrames s and v here.
并存储到 DataFrame s 和 v 中
So first, let's talk about s and the data variance.
首先来介绍下 s 和数据方差
I mentioned that from s,
根据 s
we can get an approximation of the data variance that is
我们可以获得前 n 个主成分
explained in the first and principal components.
能够解释的数据方差的近似值
The approximate explained variance is given by this formula.
这就是近似解释方差的公式
This is the sum of s squared for all selected top_n components,
它等于前 n 个成分的平分和
over the sum of squares for all components.
除以所有成分的平方和
Why are we interested in variants in the first place?
为何我们对方差感兴趣？
Why is variants so important?
为何方差很重要？
Well, the challenging part of doing dimensionality reduction with PCA,
通过 PCA 降维的难题是
is deciding on the number of top components we want to get from our data,
决定要使用数据中的前多少个成分
and eventual use in our final clustering model.
并最终用于聚类模型
Basically, we know we want to apply this PCA model to our original training data,
我们知道我们要向原始训练数据应用 PCA 模型
which will return 33 principle components.
模型将返回 33 个主成分
But we only want to use a selection of
但是我们仅想用
the top components to create a smaller feature space,
前几个成分创建更小的特征空间
which will be better for clustering our population data.
这样可以更好地聚类人口数据
So out of our 33 principal components,
在 33 个主成分中
how might we choose a good number of top components,
如何选择合适的成分数量
to include when we transform our training data?
并在转换训练数据时使用这前几个成分？
Do we choose the top five components,
选择前五个成分？
the top 10 or even more?
前十个成分？甚至更多？
Well, one thing we know is that PCA will create
我们知道 PCA 将按照导致最多方差
components in the order of causing the most to least variance.
到导致最少方差的顺序创建成分
So say we have data in three dimensions like this.
假设有这样的三维数据
This is just an illustrative example that's actually taken
这个图形示例摘自
from a PhD thesis on organizing genetic data.
一篇关于整理基因数据的博士论文
So these three-dimensions capture 100 percent of the variance in our data,
这个三维图形可以解释所有的数据方差
all of the spread up and down,
包括从上到下
left to right, and back and forth.
从左到右以及从前到后
In this image, you can see that most of this data is related,
从图中可以看出大多数数据都是相关的
all of it flows close to on a 2D plane.
都靠近一个二维平面
Just by looking at the spread of data,
仅仅通过查看数据的扩散性
we can visualize that these three dimensions have some correlation.
就可以看出这些三维数据具有某种关系
It turns out that we can create two new dimensions that are
实际上 我们可以创建新的二维数据
made up of linear combinations of the original three dimensions.
它们是原始三维数据的线性组合
These two dimensions are centered in the center of our data,
这些二维数据以原始数据的中心居中
and angled according to these PCA component lines here.
并根据这些 PCA 成分直线成一定的角度
Here, you can see that we're projecting
我们将三维数据
our three-dimensional data into this two-dimensional components space,
投射到了这个二维成分空间里
our PCA transform space.
即 PCA 转换空间
Our axes are not defined by our PCA components, one and two.
轴由 PCA 成分 PC 1 和 PC 2 确定
In this case, we're still capturing about 98 percent of our data variance,
仅使用这些二维数据
using just these two new dimensions.
我们依然捕获了 98% 的数据方差
So in this simple case,
在这个简单示例中
dimensionality reduction doesn't hurt our data representation much.
降维并没有损害多少数据表示信息
Typically, and especially for higher-dimensional data,
通常 尤其是在高维数据中
there is a noticeable trade off between the amount of variance we can
我们可以捕获的方差量
capture and the number of component dimensions we use to represent our data.
与表示数据所使用的成分数量之间有明显的权衡性
This is pretty intuitive,
这很好理解
if you discarded dimension,
如果丢失某个维度
you're going to lose some complexity in how you can represent your data.
肯定就会丢失一定的数据复杂性信息
PCA basically works with this trade off,
PCA 会考虑这种权衡性
and it's up to us to choose a number of components that both reduces
通常需要我们来选择成分数量
the dimensionality of our data and still captures most of the variance of our data.
既可以降低数据维度 又能保持最多的数据方差
Depending on your application,
这个数字可能会因
this number may vary,
具体应用而改变
but for learning general patterns in a large base of population data as we're doing here,
但是对于发现大型人口数据的一般规律来说 例如在我们的示例中
it's okay to capture around 80 percent variance.
保留约 80% 的方差就可以了
Now, one thing to note is that
需要注意的一点是
the largest s values are going to be actually at the end of this s DataFrame.
最大的 s 值将位于这个 s DataFrame 的末尾
So for example, I can look at the top five singular values,
例如 要查看前五个奇异值
by looking at a certain starting index in this s DataFrame and printing those out.
可以查看这个 s DataFrame 中的某个起始索引并输出这些值
Now, to select our top n components,
为了选择前 n 个成分
and calculate the explained variance,
并计算解释的方差量
your task will be to complete a function explained variance,
你的任务是完成函数 explained_variance
whose function will take in the entire s DataFrame that we just got,
这个函数将接受刚刚获得的整个 s DataFrame
and a number of top principal components.
以及 n_top_components 数字
This will be a value like the top one or the top five components, and so on.
这个数字表示前一个或前五个成分等等
Then you should use this approximate formula for
然后使用这个近似公式进行计算
summing square values for the top n components,
即前 n 个成分的平方和
and dividing by the sum over all components,
除以所有成分的平方和
and return the decimal percentage of the approximate explained variance.
并返回近似解释方差的百分比小数值
When you're done with this code,
编写完代码后
you can test it out here,
可以在这里测试代码
and you should be able to answer,
你将能够回答这个问题
what is the smallest number of principal components that
能够解释数据集总方差的至少 80% 的
captures at least 80 percent of the total variance in our dataset?
最小主成分数量是多少？
Try to solve this on your own.
请试着自己完成这项任务
If you want to check your work,
如果你想检查你的代码
I'll go over my solution in the next video.
请观看下个解答视频